Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Records 5685
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series III - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
  - Sub-Series A. Joint Board, 1963
    - Sub-Series 1. General Correspondence, 1963, 1963
      - Concise Village (AMCBW Bronx Co-op), 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 25)
        Brochure about housing & requests for housing Co-op Housing sponsored by AMCBW
      - Contracts - Incoming, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 26)
        Lists of shops with incoming contracts including local number and organizer initials
      - Contracts - Renewal, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 27)
        Lists of contracts expiring by month and local
      - COPE, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 28-29)
        Notices to local unions to raise money and get the vote out
      - E-F Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - Financial Contributions, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 31-32)
        Requests for money, thank you letters, etc.
      - Financial Statements, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 33)
        Statement of assets, liabilities and surplus; statement of income and expenses
      - Forums, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 34)
        Arrangement of speakers, forums were held throughout the year on various topics of interest to the union; political action; racial equality, etc.; biographical sketch of Theodore Leskes, one of the speakers
      - Fouke Fur Company, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 35)
        Clippings re above and contract with Supara; above company threw out its union workers at St. Louis to open a runaway shop in Greensville, S.C.; workers went on strike because company will not cooperate
      - Fouke Fur Company, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 36)
        Appeal from Abe Feinglass to Employees Group re helping him fight the Fouke Fur Company; gives a history of the company; list of manufacturers that will support the union in winning the strike against Fouke
      - Friedman, Sol - Personal, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 37)
        Old union newspaper Voice of the Mechanics, October 1941; photo of a dented car
      - Fur Center Synagogue, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 38)
        Brochure, newspaper clipping re center and its fund raising drive
      - Fur Information and Fashion Council, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 39-40)
        Clippings re financial difficulties of FIFC; agreements re Fur Dressing Industry contributing to FIFC Fund; FIFC publication "Picture Yourself in Furs: A Guide to Organizing a Fur Fashion Show"
      - Furriers Joint Council of New York, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 41)
      - H-I Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 42)
      - Henry, Lyndon Testimonial Dinner at Statler Hilton, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 43-44)
        Invitations, planning correspondence, program list of speakers; list of guests; invitations
      - Inter-Office Communication, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 45)
      - Joint Board Anniversary - Invitations and RSVP's, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 46-47)
      - Joint Board Anniversary, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 48)
        Speeches given at Conference/Menu/Program; Abe Feinglass speech
      - Joint Board Conference, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 49-52)
        Delegates; delegate material including newspaper copy of "I Have A Dream Speech"; pre-conference information; conference program description
      - Joint Board News, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 53)
        Newspaper published by Joint Board Fur, Leather & Machine Worker's Union - AMC&BW of NA; reports occurrences of Joint Board - 1st issues, Spring, Summer, Fall - 1963
      - K-L Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 54)
        Routine; Labor Statistic Digest published by U.S. Department of Labor
      - Legislation - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 55)
        Urge to vote for the LaVerne Bell to grant collective bargaining rights to hospital workers in New York; letter to RFK re brutal racial attack in Alabama & Mississippi from Joint Board, 4/11/63; letters from Joint Board to union members requesting support
      - Liberal Party, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 56)
        Election material; list of members; notices of meetings
      - M Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 57)
      - March on Washington, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 58-59)
        8/28/63. List of participants; various information on March; newsletter from organizer on directions for March
      - Meeting - Joint Board, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 60)
        Reminder & agendas for various meetings
      - Mimeographed Material - January - June, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 1-4)
        With Planet employees re their strike; other routine correspondence & miscellaneous routine
      - Municipal Concerts, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        Programs for outdoor concerts with union musicians
      - N - Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        Bulletin - a booklet commemorating the N.Y. Fur Workers 50th Anniversary, gives a history of the early union
      - New York City Central Labor Council AFL-CIO, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        Notices of meeting, rallies, etc.; urge for support of Civil Rights Bill and other legislation
      - N.Y. State AFL-CIO 1963 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        Urge for support for summer course for ILR for high school teachers; routine requests for support of legislation
      - P Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        S. Neil Fajita's brochure Designer's World promoting his ad campaign
      - Persian Price List, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Retirement Committee, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 11)
        Notices of meetings, activities
      - Schaffner, Henrietta Dinner (January 8, 1963) (Box 27, Folder 12)
        Surprise dinner party for above, the Secretary of the Fur & Leather Department Office
      - Scheman & Grant, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 13)
        Copy of agreement with; request for Welfare Fund payment
      - Shop Chairman list, Local 64 & Local 88, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Shop Chairman list, Local 150, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Union Label & Service Trades Council, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 16)
        Ad for Miss Union Maid doll!
      - Union Labor Report, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 17-18)
        Weekly newsletter published by Bureau of National Affairs, Special Report for September and October- December
      - Unions - Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 19)
        Local 153 Pension Fund booklet; handbill for N.Y. labor's mass picketing rally to protest lockout of newspaper plants
      - U.S. Tariff Commission - Hearings, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 20)
        Statement of Henry Foner before U.S. Tariff Commission, 12/11/63 re paragraph #1519 -- Dressed Furs & Dressed Fur Skins - no reduce imports
      - Welfare Form Letters, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 21)
        Notification of benefit changes; payments due from employees
    - Sub-Series 4. Form Letters - Joint Board, 1963
      - Notices of meeting, receptions, etc..., 1963 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - Summary of activities, decisions, meetings of Joint Board, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Sub-Series A. Joint Board, 1964
    - Sub-Series 1. General Correspondence, 1964
      - A - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - AFL-CIO Publications, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 25)
        1964 Legislative Department Fact Sheets; AFL-CIO News -N.Y. State (weekly); Industrial Union Department fact sheet/bulletin (monthly)
      - AMC&BW of NA (Chicago), 1964 (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - AMC&BW of NA (circular letters) January-May, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 27)
        International Convention info 1/20/64; civil rights program
      - AMC&BW of NA (circular letters) June-December, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 28)
        Continued boycott of F.M. Stamper Co. "Banquet & Hollywood 300" brands of frozen foods; changes in international union retirement plan
      - AMC&BW of NA (Fur & Leather Dept. Conference), 1964 (Box 27, Folder 29)
        Canadian Fur & Leather Conference at the Windsor Hotel in Montreal
      - AMC&BW of NA - Convention in Hollywood, Florida, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 30-31)
        Pre-convention arrangements; delegate listings; credentials
      - AMC&BW of NA - New York, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 32-33)
        Skin price lists; Furriers Joint Council - Reporter, July, 1963 & routine correspondence
      - AMC&BC of NA - Other than NY/Chicago, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 34)
        Press release issued by Wilbur Mills, chairman of the House Ways & Means Committee, concerning hearings on excise taxes; agreement with Great Lakes Tanning Company
      - AMC&BW of NA - Staffgrams, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 35)
        Notices of various occurrences within the union
      - American Fur Breeder, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 36)
        Magazine for January 1964 published monthly by Ojibway Press
      - B - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 37)
      - Basketball Team - schedule, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 38)
      - Brotherhood Festival and Dance, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 39-40)
        February 15, 1964. Negro History Celebration. Invitations; use of facility; speeches; clippings
      - Burt, Sam - Houses - Applications, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 41-43)
        Preliminary applications
      - Burt, Sam - Houses - General, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 44-46)
        Coney Island Co-op sponsored by Joint Board. Correspondence on planning, construction, legalities, etc. of building the housing complex
      - Burt, Sam - Houses - Groundbreaking Ceremonies, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 47)
        Feinglass speech; invitations, thank you letters
      - Burt, Sam - Houses - Publicity, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 48-50)
        Clippings from newspaper, various newsletters
      - Butchers District Council - COPE, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 51-52)
        Quotas for COPE; money contributions, listings of quotas for each local union
      - C - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 53)
      - Cammer & Shapiro, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 54)
        Memo to FLMJB that employees may be fired for refusing to cross a picket line; legal correspondence
      - Canadian-Russian Furs, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 55)
        Letter to Administrator of the Mutual Defense Assistance Act re the embargo against raw fur imports from Soviet Union; Canadians are importing them and selling to the U.S. cheaply which is undermining the American industry
      - Christmas - parties, cards, etc., 1964 (Box 27, Folder 56)
      - City of Hope, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 57)
        Fundraiser information; financial statements and other information
      - Civil Rights & Political Action Committee, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 58-59)
        January-December, 1964. Civil rights statement adopted by AFL-CIO Executive Council. Chicago, August 4, 1964; pamphlet - Equal Rights for All...the AFL-CIO Program; notices of meetings; White Thoughts on the Harlem Riot by Edna Slatkin - Comments on the R
      - Clippings, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 60)
        From newspapers re fur business & union activities
      - Community Service Committee, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 61)
        Reminder of meetings
      - Contracts Incoming, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 62)
        List of shops with
      - Contracts Expiring, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 63)
        List of shops by month and local #
      - Convalescent Home of, New York, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 64)
        Request for contribution form Samuel Schulman, new president to H. Foner
      - COPE, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 65)
        Notices of meetings, fundraisers, political agenda's, etc.
      - D-E Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 66)
        Pamphlet published by UFT & Public Education Association re better New York Schools; routine
      - Excise Taxes on leather, fur & luggage, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 67-69)
        Booklet on Excise Tax Compendium; appeal to Senate to eliminate excise taxes; newspaper clippings; summary of statements from witnesses; memo from Associated Fur Man, Inc. to Ways & Means re position on tax; Professor Harley H. Hinrichs paper - "The Case
      - F Miscellaneous - Routine, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Financial Contributions, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        Requests, thank you letters for various contributions
      - Fouke Fur Co., 1964 (Box 28, Folder 3)
        Runaway shop from St. Louis, MO to Greensville, SC; memo on Fouke Fur Co. & government contract for processing American Alaskan sealskins re illegal actions of Fouke; newspaper clippings - seal contract -4 firms are bidding; correspondence re JB trying to
      - Forums, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 4)
        Notice of community service forum on consumer problems sponsored by Joint Board
      - Fur Dressers Guild, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
        January-December 1964. Legal correspondence re unfair practices of union letting Meisal-Peskin Co. certain rights over other fur companies thus giving it a comp. advantage; Fur Guild wants to arbitrate for damages over a breach of contract due to the abov
      - Fur Information and Fashion Council, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
        Recommendation from Ruder & Finn re 1965 campaign; booklet published by FIFC entitled "How to Power Your Fur Promotions"; series of possible ads for stores: "How to reach new customers with radio", "How to put the win in windows", "How to make small space
      - G Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Guberti, Armando Reception, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        Invitation, guest list
      - H - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 11)
        Donation to Hoffa Defense Fund; letter from Lyndon Henry reporting on his trip to London
      - J Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 12)
        Jimerson Community News/January sponsored by Jimerson Board of Council re town news
      - Joint Board News, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 13)
        Winter 1964 issue & copies of individual columns that appear in the newsletter
      - K-L Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - Legislation Correspondence, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 15)
        Civil rights bill; Medicare bill; request for support of various bills
      - Liberal Party, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 16-17)
        State Legislative program of the Liberal Party of New York; notices of meetings
      - M Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 18)
        Statistics of fur production for 1963 includes production, consumption, imports, exports, etc.
      - March on Albany, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 19)
        List of demands & participants; manual; a one day demonstration to press for civil rights and social legislation in this session of the legislation
      - Meeting notices and summaries of Joint Board of Directors meetings, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 20)
        Summaries of actions taken and decisions made at each board meeting - not minutes
      - Mimeographed Material, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 21-25)
        Routine correspondence, various notices of meetings, rallies, etc.; letters to shops, etc.; copies of correspondence with the various locals and shops; campaign notices; lots of copies of correspondence that appears in other folders
      - N - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - NYS AFL-CIO, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 27)
        Credentials to convention; convention call
      - P - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 28)
        "Reorganizing Secondary Education in New York City" published by Committee on Education, Guidance and Work Part of Public Education Association Material
      - Pension & Retirement Fund - Fur Dressers & Dyers, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 29-30)
        Fund list of pensioners receiving benefits; audit information; application for retirement benefits
      - Processors Promotion Fund, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 31)
        List of contributions, bank statements and reminders for the promotion fund
      - Retirement Center, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 32-36)
        Correspondence; notices of meetings, activities, etc.
      - Retirement Center Films, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 37)
        Information on possible films to show at Center
      - Retirement Center Planning Committee, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 38-40)
        Minutes
      - Retirement Center Planning Committee, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 41)
        Notices of meeting and activities
      - S - General, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 42)
        List of max. surgical benefits; newsletter on safety from Greater New York Safety Council on safety in the home; routine
      - Sample men, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 43)
        Lists of including number of days worked
      - Severance, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 44)
        Notification of severance pay from Germaine Wasserman to union members
      - T - Miscellaneous, 1952-1964 (Box 28, Folder 45)
        March of Labor, no 8, August 1952 magazine, national monthly magazine for the active trade unionist published by March of Labor, Inc.; routine
      - U Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 46)
      - Unemployment Insurance (NJ), 1964 (Box 28, Folder 47)
        Pamphlet published by Division of Employment Security entitled "Unemployment and Disability Insurance in New Jersey, 8/1/61
      - Union Labor Report, 1963-1964 (Box 28, Folder 48-51)
        Weekly newspaper published by BNA, November 1963 - February 1964; March 1964 - April 1964; May 1964 - September 1964; October 1964 - December 1964
      - Unions - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 52)
        Letter from M. Kolbetskaya (presidium of the Central Committee of the Textile & Light Industry Workers Union of USSR) to H. Foner to establish good will and request info on the union; correspondence with other unions
      - United Medical Service, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 53)
        8/9/62. Provides more medical care coverage to organized labor than any other non-profit plan; Germaine M. Wasserman's statement against the elimination of part of their Blue Shield coverage; medical service of the union; notices of changes in coverage; L
      - United Medical Service, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 54)
        Pamphlets - information on coverage from UMS
      - V - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 55)
        Benefit information for veterans
      - Voter Registration, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 56)
        Lists of unregistered voters by local # and union shop
      - Voter Registration, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 57)
        N.Y. State Regents Literacy State - voting locations and information on how to get out the vote
      - W - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 58)
      - Welfare and Pension Plans (W&PP), 1964 (Box 28, Folder 59)
        Cammer & Shapiro, 1962-1963 correspondence; legal correspondence re funds; request for Cammer & Shapiro's opinions of funds
      - W&PP - Decisions re pension & welfare advertisement for various pension plans directed to administrator of union funds, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 60)
      - W&PP - NF Digest, Newsletter published by National Foundation of Health, Welfare & Pension Plans; Educational Conference of National Foundation, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 61-62)
        8/13-16/64
      - W&PP - Disclosure Act, 1962-1963, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 63-65)
        The Disclosure Act was amended in 1962, several reports, pamphlets & brochures were printed by the Office of Welfare and Pension Plans and U.S. Department describing the new changes in the law; a booklet on Reporting under the Welfare & Pension Plans Disc
      - W&PP - Fur Dressers & Dyers, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 1)
        Fur Dressers & Dyers Pension & Retirement Fund; minutes of trustee meetings including financial reports, list of those applying for and receiving benefits
      - W&PP - Notifications to employees of increase in benefits, 1960-64, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Workmen's Compensation - Pennsylvania, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 3)
        List of functions of the Bureau of Workmen's Compensation; request from Germaine Wasserman to Louis J. Gatzmer for him to speak about Workmen's Compensation
      - X-Z Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Sub-Series 4. Form Letters, 1964
      - Form letters, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Sub-Series 7. Worker Correspondence - Welfare Payments, etc., 1964
      - Q, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - R, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 7-10)
      - S, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 12-17)
      - T, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 18-19)
      - V, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 20-21)
      - W, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 22-26)
      - X-Y-Z, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 27-30)
      - Welfare Fund (Local 64), 1964 (Box 29, Folder 31)
        Notification of changes in benefits, move to self-insurance, requests for payments, 4/16/63 and 1964; Trustee minutes
      - Schedule for maximum surgical benefits/allowances for medical care, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Sub-Series B. Locals, 1964
    - Sub-Series 1. General Correspondence, 1964, 1964
      - Pension & Retirement Fund (Local 150) 1964 (Box 29, Folder 33)
        Request to complete Disclosure Act Forms; routine
      - United Mechanics Welfare Fund (Local 150) 1964 (Box 29, Folder 34)
        Schedule of maximum surgical benefits/allowances for medical care; recommendations for amendment to Local 150 Welfare Fund (i.e. in benefits); notifications of increases
      - United Mechanics Welfare Fund (Local 150) 1964 (Box 29, Folder 35-36)
        New plan for self-insurance instead of using United Medical Services; notification of change to employees
    - Sub-Series 2. Elections, 1964
      - General election information including election procedures, dates, etc., 1964 (Box 29, Folder 37)
      - Local 48F, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 38)
        Sample ballots, election results, etc.
      - Local 61F, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 39)
      - Local 64F, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 40-42)
        Notification of nomination (to election) to members
      - Local 64F, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 43)
        Questionnaire for nominees
      - Local 64F, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 44-45)
        List of nominees, members of election committee and conference delegates, results and sample ballots
      - Local 88F, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 46)
        Sample ballots, election results
      - Local 150F, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 47)
  - Sub-Series A. Joint Board, 1965
    - Sub-Series 1. General Correspondence, 1965
      - A Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 48-49)
      - AFL-CIO Convention, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 50)
        Election propaganda for Pat Gorman to win a seat on the AFL-CIO Executive Council; Chicago Civic News, a newsletter published by Chicago Committee of One Hundred - contains articles on Patrick E. Gorman; pamphlet entitled "American & Soviet Economy, Contr
      - AFL-CIO Convention, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 51)
        Booklet - "Question and Answers on American Labor & World Affairs, AFL-CIO; booklet - "The Greater Danger" - The Post-Stalin Pattern for Communist World Conquest, AFL-CIO; booklet on the history of the garment industry published by ILGWU "Signature of 450
      - AMC&BW of NA, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 52)
        Report on P. Gorman's loss in his bid to win a seat on the AFL-CIO Executive Council
      - AMC&BW of NA - Chicago, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 53)
        Request or strike benefits for Unity Sewing Supply from Local 150; letters to P. Gorman from various people stating they wish he would have been elected to the Council
      - AMC&BW of NA - Circular Letters, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 54)
        List of convention resolutions; manual of common procedures; constitutional amendment to cover mergers, consolidations and amalgamations; strike against Hy-Plains Dressed Beef Co. at Dodge City, Kansas
      - AMC&BW of NA, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 55)
        Statement by Thomas J. Lloyd, President of AMC&BW & Marvin Hook, Vice President, Retail Dept., AMC&BW to National Commission on Food Marketing re making the commission a permanent institution of government
      - AMC&BW of NA, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 56)
        Data on membership numbers
      - AMC&BW of NA - Local 27, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 57)
        Contract between Local 27 and FLMJB re representation, affiliations, etc.
      - AMC&BW of NA - Local 186 (Seattle), 1965 (Box 29, Folder 58)
        Michael Dederer of Seattle Fur Exchange letter to H. Foner re contract between Local 64 and FLMJB and NY Auction Co. (Minnesota)
      - AMC&BW of NA - Other than Chicago, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 59-60)